{
  "Quizzes": [
    {
      "quizz_title": "Lesson 1: FortiGate Firewall and Security Basics",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "How does FortiGate check content for spam or malicious websites?",
          "answer": [
            "Local verification using a downloaded web filter database locally on FortiGate",
            "Live queries to FortiGuard over UDP or HTTPS"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Live queries to FortiGuard over UDP or HTTPS"
        },
        {
          "question": "What must be selected in the Source field of a firewall policy?",
          "answer": [
            "At least one source user and one source address object",
            "At least one address object or ISDB"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "At least one address object or ISDB"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the purpose of the policy lookup feature on FortiGate?",
          "answer": [
            "To find a matching policy based on input criteria",
            "To block traffic based on input criteria"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "To find a matching policy based on input criteria"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a more accurate description of a modern firewall?",
          "answer": [
            "A device that inspects network traffic at an entry point to the internet and within a simple, easily defined network perimeter",
            "A multifunctional device that inspects network traffic from the perimeter or internally, within a network that has many different entry points"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "A multifunctional device that inspects network traffic from the perimeter or internally, within a network that has many different entry points"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which solution specific to Fortinet enhances performance and reduces latency for specific features and traffic?",
          "answer": [
            "Increased RAM and CPU power",
            "Acceleration hardware, called SPUs"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Acceleration hardware, called SPUs"
        },
        {
          "question": "What criteria does FortiGate use to match traffic to a firewall policy?",
          "answer": [
            "Security profiles",
            "Source and destination interfaces"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Source and destination interfaces"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which protocol does FortiGate use to download antivirus and IPS packages?",
          "answer": [
            "UDP",
            "TCP"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "TCP"
        },
        {
          "question": "If you configure a firewall policy with the any interface, you can view the firewall policy list only in which view?",
          "answer": [
            "The By Sequence View",
            "The Interface Pair View"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The By Sequence View"
        },
        {
          "question": "As a best security practice when configuring administrative access to FortiGate, which protocol should you disable?",
          "answer": [
            "Telnet",
            "SSH"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Telnet"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following naming formats is correct when configuring a name for a firewall address object?",
          "answer": [
            "Good(Training)",
            "Good_Training"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Good_Training"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "quizz_title": "Lesson 2: FortiGate NAT Configuration and Behavior",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is a benefit of using NAT?",
          "answer": [
            "Prevents depletion of IPv4 public address",
            "Enhanced content inspection"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Prevents depletion of IPv4 public address"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is the default VIP type?",
          "answer": [
            "static-nat",
            "load-balance"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "static-nat"
        },
        {
          "question": "What happens if there is no matching central SNAT policy or no central SNAT policy configured?",
          "answer": [
            "NAT is not be applied to the firewall session.",
            "The egress interface IP is used."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "NAT is not be applied to the firewall session."
        },
        {
          "question": "An administrator wants to check the total number of TCP sessions for an IP pool named INTERNAL. Which CLI command should the administrator use?",
          "answer": [
            "diagnose firewall ippool-all list INTERNAL",
            "diagnose firewall ippool-all stats INTERNAL"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "diagnose firewall ippool-all stats INTERNAL"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement is true?",
          "answer": [
            "Both central NAT and firewall policy NAT can be enabled together.",
            "Central NAT is not enabled by default."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Central NAT is not enabled by default."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the default IP pool type?",
          "answer": [
            "One-to-one",
            "Overload"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Overload"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement about NAT66 is true?",
          "answer": [
            "It is used to translate addresses between two IPv6 networks.",
            "It is used to translate addresses between two IPv4 networks."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "It is used to translate addresses between two IPv6 networks."
        }
      ]
    },
     {
      "quizz_title": "Lesson 3: FortiGate Authentication and Logging",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which firewall authentication method does FortiGate support?",
          "answer": [
            "Local password authentication",
            "Biometric authentication"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Local password authentication"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which type of logs are application control, web filter, and antivirus?",
          "answer": [
            "Security",
            "Event"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Security"
        },
        {
          "question": "What happens when logs roll?",
          "answer": [
            "It lowers the space requirements needed to contain those logs.",
            "They are uploaded to an FTP server."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "It lowers the space requirements needed to contain those logs."
        },
        {
          "question": "A remote LDAP user is trying to authenticate with a username and password. How does FortiGate verify the login credentials?",
          "answer": [
            "FortiGate queries its own database for user credentials.",
            "FortiGate sends the user-entered credentials to the remote server for verification."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "FortiGate sends the user-entered credentials to the remote server for verification."
        },
        {
          "question": "If you enable reliable logging, which transport protocol will FortiGate use?",
          "answer": [
            "TCP",
            "UDP"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "TCP"
        },
        {
          "question": "Guest accounts are most commonly used for which purposes?",
          "answer": [
            "To provide temporary visitor access to corporate network resources",
            "To provide temporary visitor access to wireless networks"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "To provide temporary visitor access to wireless networks"
        },
        {
          "question": "When FortiGate uses a RADIUS server for remote authentication, which statement about RADIUS is true?",
          "answer": [
            "FortiGate must query the remote RADIUS server using the distinguished name (dn).",
            "RADIUS group memberships are provided by vendor-specific attributes (VSAs) configured on the RADIUS server"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "RADIUS group memberships are provided by vendor-specific attributes (VSAs) configured on the RADIUS server"
        },
        {
          "question": "The log ________ contains fields that are common to all log types, such as originating date and time, log identifier, log category, and VDOM.",
          "answer": [
            "body",
            "header"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "header"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which protocol does FortiGate use to send encrypted logs to FortiAnalyzer?",
          "answer": [
            "OFTPS",
            "SSL"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "OFTPS"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which storage type is preferred for logging?",
          "answer": [
            "Hard drive",
            "Remote logging"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Remote logging"
        }
      ]
    },
     {
      "quizz_title": "Lesson 4: SSL Inspection and Web Filtering",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which certificate extension and value is required in the FortiGate CA certificate in order to enable full SSL inspection?",
          "answer": [
            "CRL DP=ca_arl.arl",
            "cA=True"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "cA=True"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which configuration requires FortiGate to act as a CA for full SSL inspection?",
          "answer": [
            "Multiple clients connecting to multiple servers",
            "Protecting the SSL server"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Multiple clients connecting to multiple servers"
        },
        {
          "question": "How does NGFW policy-based mode differ from profile-based mode?",
          "answer": [
            "Policy-based flow inspection supports web profile overrides.",
            "Policy-based flow inspection defines URL filters directly in the firewall policy."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Policy-based flow inspection defines URL filters directly in the firewall policy."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement about proxy-based web filtering is true?",
          "answer": [
            "It requires more resources than flow-based",
            "It transparently analyzes the TCP flow of the traffic"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "It requires more resources than flow-based"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is required by FortiGate to configure YouTube video filtering?",
          "answer": [
            "Username",
            "YouTube API key"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "YouTube API key"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which feature can be used for restricting websites or images from search results?",
          "answer": [
            "Web Content Filtering",
            "Search Engine Filtering"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Search Engine Filtering"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which action in video filtering will prevent the videos from playing?",
          "answer": [
            "Block",
            "Deny"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Block"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which attribute or extension identifies the owner of a certificate?",
          "answer": [
            "The unique serial number in the certificate",
            "The subject name in the certificate"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The subject name in the certificate"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is used for matching content in Web Content Filtering?",
          "answer": [
            "Perl regular expressions",
            "Boolean operators"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Perl regular expressions"
        },
        {
          "question": "How does FortiGate determine if a certificate has been revoked?",
          "answer": [
            "It retrieves the CRL from a directory server.",
            "It checks the CRL that resides on FortiGate."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "It checks the CRL that resides on FortiGate."
        }
      ]
    },
     {
      "quizz_title": "Lesson 6: Application Control and Antivirus",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the default scanning behavior for files over 10 MB?",
          "answer": [
            "Block all large files that exceed the buffer threshold",
            "Allow the file without scanning"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Allow the file without scanning"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement about application control in an NGFW policy-based configuration is true?",
          "answer": [
            "The application control profile must be applied to firewall policies.",
            "Applications are applied directly to the security policies."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Applications are applied directly to the security policies."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which databases can be manually selected for use in antivirus scanning?",
          "answer": [
            "Extended and Extreme",
            "Quick, Normal, and Extreme"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Extended and Extreme"
        },
        {
          "question": "If antivirus, grayware, and AI scans are enabled, in what order are they performed?",
          "answer": [
            "AI scan, followed by grayware scan, followed by antivirus scan",
            "Antivirus scan, followed by grayware scan, followed by AI scan"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Antivirus scan, followed by grayware scan, followed by AI scan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which SSL/SSH inspection method is recommended for use with application control scanning to improve application detection?",
          "answer": [
            "Certificate-based inspection profile",
            "Deep-inspection profile"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Deep-inspection profile"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which protocol does FortiGate use with FortiGuard to receive updates for application control?",
          "answer": [
            "TCP",
            "UDP"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "TCP"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement about the application control database is true?",
          "answer": [
            "The application control database is separate from the IPS database.",
            "The application control database must be updated manually."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The application control database is separate from the IPS database."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which type of inspection mode can be offloaded using NTurbo hardware acceleration?",
          "answer": [
            "Flow-based",
            "Proxy-based"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Flow-based"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement about the HTTP block page for application control is true?",
          "answer": [
            "It can be used only for web applications.",
            "It works for all types of applications."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "It can be used only for web applications."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement about application control is true?",
          "answer": [
            "Application control is unable to scan P2P architecture traffic.",
            "Application control uses the IPS engine to scan traffic for application patterns."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Application control uses the IPS engine to scan traffic for application patterns."
        }
      ]
    },
     {
      "quizz_title": "Lesson 7: Intrusion Prevention and Security Fabric",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which feature requires full SSL inspection to maximize its detection capability?",
          "answer": [
            "DoS",
            "WAF"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "WAF"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which behavior is a characteristic of a DoS attack?",
          "answer": [
            "Attempts to exploit a known application vulnerability",
            "Attempts to overload a server with TCP SYN packets"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Attempts to overload a server with TCP SYN packets"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which combination of devices must participate in the Security Fabric?",
          "answer": [
            "A FortiMail and two or more FortiGate devices",
            "A FortiAnalyzer and two or more FortiGate devices"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "A FortiAnalyzer and two or more FortiGate devices"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Fortinet Security Fabric?",
          "answer": [
            "A device that can manage all your firewalls",
            "A Fortinet solution that enables communication and visibility among devices of your network"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "A Fortinet solution that enables communication and visibility among devices of your network"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which DoS anomaly sensor can be used to detect and block the probing attempts of a port scanner?",
          "answer": [
            "tcp_syn_flood",
            "tcp_port_scan"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "tcp_port_scan"
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the two mandatory settings of the Security Fabric configuration?",
          "answer": [
            "Fabric name and Security Fabric role",
            "Fabric name and FortiManager IP address"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Fabric name and Security Fabric role"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which IPS action allows traffic and logs the activity?",
          "answer": [
            "Monitor",
            "Allow"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Monitor"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which IPS component is updated most frequently?",
          "answer": [
            "IPS signature database",
            "Protocol decoders"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "IPS signature database"
        },
        {
          "question": "From where do you authorize a device to participate in the Security Fabric?",
          "answer": [
            "From the root FortiGate",
            "From the downstream FortiGate"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "From the root FortiGate"
        },
        {
          "question": "Why should an administrator extend the Security Fabric to other devices?",
          "answer": [
            "To eliminate the need to purchase licenses for FortiGate devices in the Security Fabric",
            "To provide a single pane of glass for management and reporting purposes"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "To provide a single pane of glass for management and reporting purposes"
        }
      ]
    }

  ]
}
